<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The jolly gentleman's frolick: or, The city ramble. Being, an account of a young gallant, who wager'd to pass any of the watches, without giving them an answer; but being stop'd by the constable at Cripple-gate, was sent to the counter, afterwards had before my lord mayor, and was clear'd by the intercession of my lord mayor's daughter. To a pleasant new tune.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1690-1uuu?</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B03924</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing J893</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide EBB65H[142]</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99887183</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99887183</idno>
            <idno type="VID">181891</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B03924)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 181891)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; A2:3[142])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The jolly gentleman's frolick: or, The city ramble. Being, an account of a young gallant, who wager'd to pass any of the watches, without giving them an answer; but being stop'd by the constable at Cripple-gate, was sent to the counter, afterwards had before my lord mayor, and was clear'd by the intercession of my lord mayor's daughter. To a pleasant new tune.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.) : ill. (woodcuts).  </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for C[harles]. Bates, at the White-Hart in West-Smithfield.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[not before 1690]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Verse: "Give your ear to a frolicksome ditty ..."</note>
                  <note>Date, place of publication and publisher's name from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Harvard University, Houghton Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Ballads, English --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-09</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-02</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-02</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="ballad">
            <pb facs="tcp:181891:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 17 -->
            <head>The Jolly Gentleman's FROLICK: OR, The City Ramble.</head>
            <argument>
               <p>Being, An Account of a young Gallant, who Wager'd to paſs any of the Watches, without giving them an Anſwer; but being ſtop'd by the Conſtable at <hi>Cripple-gate,</hi> was ſent to the <hi>Counter,</hi> afterwards had before my Lord Mayor, and was Clear'd by the Interceſſion of my Lord Mayors Daughter.</p>
            </argument>
            <opener>To a Pleaſant New Tune.</opener>
            <p>
               <figure/>
            </p>
            <p>
               <figure/>
            </p>
            <lg>
               <l>GIve ear to a Frollickſome Ditty,</l>
               <l>of one that a Wager did lay</l>
               <l>He'd paſs any Watch in the City,</l>
               <l>and never a Word he wou'd ſay</l>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>But, Dal, derra, rarra, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                     </hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The Conſtable ſpake to his Watch-men,</l>
               <l>brave Boys, it is my Delight,</l>
               <l>And Orders have for to catch Men,</l>
               <l>who Ramble too late in the Night.</l>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>The <hi>Humour,</hi> &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The Streets do Eccho, we hear, Boys,</l>
               <l>with Mad-men coming along;</l>
               <l>My Staff is ready, ne'r fear, Boys,</l>
               <l>we'll make 'um alter their Song.</l>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>The <hi>Humour,</hi> &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Stand, ſtand, ſays the Bell-man,</l>
               <l>the Conſtable now come before,</l>
               <l>And if a juſt Story you tell, Man,</l>
               <l>I'll Light you home to your own Door:</l>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>The <hi>Humour,</hi> &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>This is a very late ſeaſon,</l>
               <l>which ſurely no Honeſt Men keep,</l>
               <l>And therefore 'tis but juſt reaſon,</l>
               <l>that you in the <hi>Counter</hi> ſhould ſleep.</l>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>The <hi>Humour,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>(Sad.)</hi>
                     </hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Take away this ſame Fellow,</l>
               <l>and him to the <hi>Counter</hi> convey,</l>
               <l>Although his Frollick is mellow,</l>
               <l>he ſomething to Morrow will ſay.</l>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>The <hi>Humour,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>(Sad.)</hi>
                     </hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Open the Gate, make no ſcorning,</l>
               <l>take Charge of your Priſoner there,</l>
               <l>And we will ſoon in the morning,</l>
               <l>appear before my Lord Mayor.</l>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>The <hi>Humour,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>(Sad.)</hi>
                     </hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>A Bottle of Claret I'll fill, Sir,</l>
               <l>ſome P<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>pes of Tobacco, beſide.</l>
               <l>And if that it now be your will, Sir,</l>
               <l>a Bed for you ſoon we'll provide.</l>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>The <hi>Humour,</hi> &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>This Frollick ſoon Eccho'd the Priſon,</l>
               <l>the Debters his Garniſh would have;</l>
               <l>Without demanding the reaſon,</l>
               <l>whate're they-requir'd, he gave.</l>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>The <hi>Humour,</hi> &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The Conſtable ſoon the next day, Sir,</l>
               <l>this Comical matter to clear,</l>
               <l>The Gentleman hurrys ſtraightways, ſir,</l>
               <l>before my Lord Mayor to appear.</l>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>The <hi>Humour,</hi> &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>My Lord, give ear to my Story,</l>
               <l>while I the truth do relate,</l>
               <l>The Gentleman ſtanding before ye,</l>
               <l>was ſeiz'd by me at <hi>Cripple-gate.</hi>
               </l>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>The <hi>Humour,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>(Sad.)</hi>
                     </hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>I nothing could hear but his Singing,</l>
               <l>wherefore in the <hi>Counter</hi> he lay,</l>
               <l>And therefore this morning I bring him</l>
               <l>to hear what your Lordſhip will ſay.</l>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>The <hi>Humour,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>(Sad.)</hi>
                     </hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Come Friend, the Caſe does appear now,</l>
                  <l>that you was in a Mad Fit,</l>
                  <l>I hope that you may be clear now,</l>
                  <l>ſince Sleep has reſtor'd you your Wit.</l>
                  <lg type="refrain">
                     <l>
                        <hi>The <hi>Humour,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>(Sad.)</hi>
                        </hi>
                     </l>
                  </lg>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>This Gentleman ſure is Diſtracted,</l>
                  <l>he's over-heated his Brain,</l>
                  <l>Since he thus ſilly has acted,</l>
                  <l>to th' <hi>Counter</hi> I'll ſend him again.</l>
                  <lg type="refrain">
                     <l>
                        <hi>The <hi>Humour,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>(Sad.)</hi>
                        </hi>
                     </l>
                  </lg>
               </lg>
               <l>A Priſon ſure it will tame him,</l>
               <l>and bring him ſoon to his Senſe,</l>
               <l>There's nothing elſe can reclaim him,</l>
               <l>from this his notorious Offence,</l>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>The <hi>Humour,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>(Sad,)</hi>
                     </hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>O then beſpake my Lord's Daughter,</l>
               <l>and for him did thus Interceed,</l>
               <l>Dear Father, you'll hear that hereafter,</l>
               <l>this is but a Wager, indeed.</l>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>The <hi>Humour,</hi> &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Therefore be pleaſed, kind Father,</l>
               <l>to hear one word more of me,</l>
               <l>And ſhew to me ſo much favour,</l>
               <l>this Gentleman may be ſet free.</l>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>The <hi>Humour,</hi> &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Well, Daughter, I grant your Petition,</l>
               <l>the Gentleman home may repair,</l>
               <l>But yet 'tis upon this Condition,</l>
               <l>of paying my Officers there.</l>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>The <hi>Humour,</hi> &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Come Sir, your Fees we require,</l>
               <l>you free'd are now by the Court,</l>
               <l>And all that we do deſire,</l>
               <l>you'll find out ſome other new Sport.</l>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>The <hi>Humour,</hi> &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Thus ſeeing he might be Releaſed,</l>
               <l>if he his Fees did but pay,</l>
               <l>He then was very well pleaſed,</l>
               <l>and ſo went Singing awa<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>,</l>
               <lg type="refrain">
                  <l>
                     <hi>The <hi>Humour,</hi> &amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </lg>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>Printed for</hi> C. Bates, at the White-Hart in Weſt-Smithfield.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
